ALEXIS ADRIAN CABRERA PEREIRA

alexis.adrianc@gmail.com | +598 93328535 | 1545 Uruguay Av., Montevideo, Uruguay

SUMMARY

Software Developer with eight years of experience in designing and developing user interfaces, testing and debugging. Dedicated to driving innovation with the ability to follow industry and technological trends, and facilitating early adoption of innovations. I like being involved in projects that require me to work outside of my comfort and knowledge, because continuing to learn new development languages and techniques is important to me and to the success of your organization.

EXPERIENCE

Nov 2018 - Current

Senior Odoo Consultant | Quanam | Montevideo, Uruguay

- Test of automation and improve the performance (flake8, pep8, pylint, odoo-pylint)
- Collaborated with senior-level developers to develop projects for web application throughout various phases of project lifecycle.
- Maintained existing code and functionality during assimilation into ongoing operations of web business.
- Support maintenance programming development for web applications.

Jan 2013 - Jun 2018

Software Developer | Application Company - DESOFT | Santiago de Cuba, Cuba

- Excelled in rapid application development and management of technological issues for assigned projects, earning the highest customer satisfaction rating for all software solutions delivered.
- Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of products through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Improved database design skills and fluent in SQL statements.
- Participated in user requirements meetings in order to transform client needs into proposed application designs.

Sep 2012 - Dec 2012

Junior Web Developer | Software Development Center - CEDESA | Santiago de Cuba, Cuba

- Developed application prototypes and participated in client meetings.
- Analyzed user requirements, and translated client needs into application design.

EDUCATION LANGUAGES

Sep 2007 - Jul 2012 Computer Science Engineer University of Informatic Sciences | Spanish Native

La Havana, Cuba English Professional French Elementary

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Dec 2020 Docker, from beginner to expert Udemy

Jul 2020 Basic SQL Certified aics | Asociación Internacional de Calidad de Software

Jul 2020 Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate (SFPC) CertiProf

GENERAL SKILLS TECHNICAL SKILLS

Communication TOOLS

Organized PyCharm, NetBeans,

Troubleshoot SOFTWARE

Analytical Skills ERP Odoo, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redmine, CMS Drupal.

Teamwork PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Fast learner Python, Django, Java, SQL, PHP, XML, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Linux, Microsoft Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10.

CLOUD-BASED TECHNOLOGIES

AWS, Docker